# Christopher Goodwin

User Experience Developer

802-540-5036

hello@christophergoodwin.me
christophergoodwin.me
linkedin.com/in/goodwinc

## **About**

I believe in building a web that works for everyone, everywhere. Using primarily HTML & CSS, I write performant and maintainable code that's fast, responsive, and accessible.

I've had the privilege of building world class web experiences with companies such as Apple, Netflix, CIEE, and Sparta Science.

# **Experience**

## Senior User Experience Developer at DockYard

2016 - Present

- Leading UX development on internal and public-facing web apps with companies including Apple, Netflix, and Sparta Science
- · Working collaboratively with team members to translate designs into semantic, reliable code
- Writing and auditing code to ensure accessibility, performance, and graceful degradation
- Refining coding standards while growing company understanding of best practices
- · Mentoring and teaching colleagues seeking improvement in front-end skills
- · Co-working remotely with an entirely distributed team

## Front End Web Developer at Council on International Education Exchange

2014 - 2016

- Worked with a team to design and develop responsive and accessible websites
- · Estimated timelines and scoped work to meet project deadlines
- · Maintained and updated over 20 marketing websites

#### Freelance Web Developer

2011 - 2014

- · Designed, developed, and maintained corporate and personal websites
- · Spent time with clients to learn about their needs and products
- Enabled clients to create and grow their brands
- · Trained clients to update and maintain their sites for long term use

# Skills

# Education

0	HTML and CSS expertise with tocus on semantic,
	maintainable code

- Robust understanding of accessibility best practices
- Design experience and familiarity with modern design software
- Experience building and maintaining design systems and component libraries
- Background in Javascript development
- Strong knowledge of Git and version control
- Experience working remotely
- · Photography and video production background

## BS in Web and Interactive Media

Pennsylvania College of Technology
 The Art Institute of New England
 2011 - 2014
 2010 - 2011

### **Certificate of Completion**

Center for Technology, Essex
 2008 - 2010